<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on purpleidea.com</title>
    <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on purpleidea.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <atom:link href="https://purpleidea.com/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dinner</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/dinner/</guid>
      <description>This page has some more information about the annual dinner.&#xA;Statistics Year Meals served Location 2024 980 (550+430) Concordia 2023 893 (584+309) St. Ignatius of Loyola 2022 &gt; 731 (counting stopped before the end) St. Ignatius of Loyola 2021 cancelled N/A 2020 0 (covid) N/A 2019 1126 St. Ignatius of Loyola 2018 1097 (742+355) St. Ignatius of Loyola 2017 1035 St. Ignatius of Loyola 2016 899 St. Ignatius of Loyola 2015 1222 St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DJ</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/dj/</guid>
      <description>I DJ occasionally. Mostly for fun, as I like to put on a good show. I invest almost 100% of my performance fees into paying for show consumables (fire, smoke, bubbles, etc&amp;hellip;) and for buying new equipment to improve the shows.&#xA;I play almost entirely Old School Hip-Hop and Rap, combined with some Break Beats and occasional slow jams.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to hire me to play at your bar, club, or venue, please contact me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/donate/</guid>
      <description>If you like my blog, and you like my code, please leave me a tip!&#xA;You can also donate money via my patreon.&#xA;Funds and other resources give me more time to spend on code and articles for you!&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m often in need of hardware, so if you have something you can donate or sponsor, please let me know.&#xA;If your company wants to fly me somewhere to come hack on my code in your office, that could be arranged.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to cook a turkey</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/how-to-cook-a-turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/how-to-cook-a-turkey/</guid>
      <description>What follows are instructions for cooking a turkey. This page is mostly intended for folks that donate turkeys to the annual dinner.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Turkey&amp;rdquo; (based on an article from Gourmet Magazine, November 2005) Instructions If frozen, make sure the turkey has been thawing the refrigerator for one or two days depending on the size of the turkey. You can remove it one hour before cooking to allow it to warm up even more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring Program</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/mentoring-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/mentoring-program/</guid>
      <description>I run a very small mentoring program. The format has been evolving over time. The program is intended to be very difficult, but fulfilling. Some information about the program can be found on this page.&#xA;I currently offer two streams, each with a different specialization:&#xA;Stream A: Software Engineering &amp;amp; Programming&#xA;Stream B: Systems Administration &amp;amp; DevOps&#xA;I started this program because I was disappointed with the quality of many new hackers these days, and in particular the shift away from strong basic skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Technical Problems</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/open-technical-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/open-technical-problems/</guid>
      <description>What follows is my personal list of what I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to call &amp;ldquo;Open Technical Problems&amp;rdquo;. Each of these items is a description of an open technical problem that I think would be really excellent to have solved. I believe all of these could be reasonably easy to solve if someone has the time, money, and will to do so.&#xA;If you are working on any of these ideas, of if one is solved, please let me know!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pendeli&#39;s Pizza Cote-St-Luc</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/pendelis-pizza-cote-st-luc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/pendelis-pizza-cote-st-luc/</guid>
      <description>Their telephone operator usually sounds very unhappy, but their pizza is fairly good. Ask them not to burn it! I recommend the &amp;ldquo;cheese and tomato&amp;rdquo;, aka plain. Tell them The Technical Blog of James sent you.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s the most recent menu:&#xA;I posted this because there&amp;rsquo;s no menu to be found online.&#xA;Happy Hacking!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seymour Smith - Dorothy</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/seymour-smith-dorothy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/seymour-smith-dorothy/</guid>
      <description>My favourite piece of piano music is called &amp;ldquo;Dorothy&amp;rdquo; by &amp;ldquo;Seymour Smith&amp;rdquo;. My grandmother [1] used to play it to me when I was young. When she died, I asked if I could keep the piano music.&#xA;If you know anything about Seymour Smith, have a copy of any of his sheet music, or would like to send me a recording of Dorothy of any of his other music, please contact me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Technical CAPTCHA</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/the-technical-captcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/the-technical-captcha/</guid>
      <description>This was intended to be a CAPTCHA for recruiters.&#xA;The CAPTCHA Comment or write a question on one of my technical articles. Contact me. If your comment was good, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a reply back! It need not be long, but you do get points for cleverness if it asks an interesting question, or makes light of a fun corner case that I haven&amp;rsquo;t covered. The clever part about this, is that you get to think of it as a way of quizzing me, and I get to engage with people whose interest is technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/misc/wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/misc/wisdom/</guid>
      <description> An ideal language allows us to express easily what is useful for the programming task, and at the same time makes it difficult to write what leads to incomprehensible or incorrect programs. – Nico Habermann </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
