<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nfs on purpleidea.com</title>
    <link>https://purpleidea.com/tags/nfs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nfs on purpleidea.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 23:00:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://purpleidea.com/tags/nfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically deploying GlusterFS with Puppet-Gluster &#43; Vagrant!</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2014/01/08/automatically-deploying-glusterfs-with-puppet-gluster-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 23:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2014/01/08/automatically-deploying-glusterfs-with-puppet-gluster-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>Puppet-Gluster was always about automating the deployment of GlusterFS. Getting your own Puppet server and the associated infrastructure running was never included &amp;ldquo;out of the box&amp;rdquo;. Today, it is! (This is big news!)
I&amp;rsquo;ve used Vagrant to automatically build these GlusterFS clusters. I&amp;rsquo;ve tested this with Fedora 20, and vagrant-libvirt. This won&amp;rsquo;t work with Fedora 19 because of bz#876541. I recommend first reading my earlier articles for Vagrant and Fedora:   Vagrant on Fedora with libvirt   Vagrant vsftp and other tricks   Vagrant clustered SSH and &amp;lsquo;screen&amp;rsquo;   Once you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with the material in the above articles, we can continue&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant vsftp and other tricks</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2013/12/21/vagrant-vsftp-and-other-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 11:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2013/12/21/vagrant-vsftp-and-other-tricks/</guid>
      <description>As I previously wrote, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with Vagrant on Fedora with libvirt, and have even been submitting, patches and issues! (This &amp;ldquo;closed&amp;rdquo; issue needs solving!) Here are some of the tricks that I&amp;rsquo;ve used while hacking away.
Default provider:
I should have mentioned this in my earlier article but I forgot: If you&amp;rsquo;re always using the same provider, you might want to set it as the default. In my case I&amp;rsquo;m using vagrant-libvirt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first release of puppet-shorewall</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2013/10/21/first-release-of-puppet-shorewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 00:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2013/10/21/first-release-of-puppet-shorewall/</guid>
      <description>Oh, hi there.
In case you&amp;rsquo;re interested, I&amp;rsquo;ve just made a first release of my puppet-shorewall module. This isn&amp;rsquo;t meant as an exhaustive shorewall module, but it does provide most of the usual functionality that most users need.
In particular, it&amp;rsquo;s the module dependency that I use for many of my other puppet modules that provide firewalling. This is probably where you&amp;rsquo;re most likely to consume it.
In general most modules just implement shorewall::rule, so if you really don&amp;rsquo;t want to use this code, you can implement that signature yourself, or not use automatic firewalling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh releases! puppet-ipa, puppet-nfs, puppet-gluster</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2013/06/23/fresh-releases-puppet-ipa-puppet-nfs-puppet-gluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 09:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2013/06/23/fresh-releases-puppet-ipa-puppet-nfs-puppet-gluster/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a little slow in making release announcements, so here&amp;rsquo;s some news:
I&amp;rsquo;ve just released the third stage of my puppet-ipa module. At the moment it now supports installation, managing of hosts, and managing of services. It integrates with my puppet-nfs module to allow you to easily setup and run an NFSv4 kerberized server and client.
While we&amp;rsquo;re at it, that&amp;rsquo;s some more news: I&amp;rsquo;ve just released a puppet-nfs module to make your /etc/exports management easier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>