<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rhel on purpleidea.com</title>
    <link>https://purpleidea.com/tags/rhel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rhel on purpleidea.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 15:09:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://purpleidea.com/tags/rhel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant and Oh-My-Vagrant on RHEL7</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2015/08/11/vagrant-and-oh-my-vagrant-on-rhel7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 15:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2015/08/11/vagrant-and-oh-my-vagrant-on-rhel7/</guid>
      <description>My employer keeps paying me, which I appreciate, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to spend some time to make sure RHEL7 customers get a great developer experience! So here&amp;rsquo;s how to make vagrant, vagrant-libvirt and Oh-My-Vagrant work on RHEL 7+. The same steps should work for CentOS 7+.
I&amp;rsquo;ll first paste the commands you need to run, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what&amp;rsquo;s happening for those that are interested:
# run these commands, and then get hacking!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building RHEL Vagrant Boxes with Vagrant-Builder</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2015/02/23/building-rhel-vagrant-boxes-with-vagrant-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 22:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2015/02/23/building-rhel-vagrant-boxes-with-vagrant-builder/</guid>
      <description>Vagrant is a great tool for development, but Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) customers have typically been left out, because it has been impossible to get RHEL boxes! It would be extremely elegant if hackers could quickly test and prototype their code on the same OS as they&amp;rsquo;re running in production.
Secondly, when hacking on projects that have a long initial setup phase (eg: a long rpm install) it would be excellent if hackers could roll their own modified base boxes, so that certain common operations could be re-factored out into the base image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now syndicated on “Planet Fedora”</title>
      <link>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2013/12/09/now-syndicated-on-planet-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 19:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://purpleidea.com/blog/2013/12/09/now-syndicated-on-planet-fedora/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m now syndicated on the Fedora Project planet. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read through my blog yet, let me introduce myself, I&amp;rsquo;m James, and I write The Technical Blog of James.
I&amp;rsquo;m a sysadmin, DevOps/Puppet hacker, I.T./network architect and physiologist. Hi! I run Fedora as my primary desktop, but I also use it for servers, particularly for development before future versions of RHEL and CentOS release.
I&amp;rsquo;m most well-known for Puppet-Gluster, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also written a decent Puppet-IPA (FreeIPA) module.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>